### jobs@xavierdury.net +32-(0)486-535020

# **Xavier Dury**

## Civil Engineer in Computer Science

#### **Profile**

I am a civil engineer with more than 15 years of professional experience working on IT projects (mostly in Java) as analyst, developer and architect. I have a good grasp of technology and trained for project management at the University of Brussels. I prefer working as an employee rather than a contractor as I really like to understand the domain I am working in and favor long-term commitment on projects where I can participate in design, implementation and maintenance. I lean toward working on meaningful projects which benefit the community (healthcare, social security, public transportation, public services/e-government, scientific research, etc.). I am a big proponent of open source solutions for which I try to contribute back.

#### **Work experiences**

Java Team Leader / Architect @ Federal Pension Service (SFPD)

[2014-04—today]

xavierdury.net

**Pension Portal** Public sector career data centralization and management application

Java Team Leader, Architect

JavaEE 6 (JSF, JPA, JMS, CDI, EJB), FOP, Maven, AngularJS, Git, Gerrit, JBossAS 7, Oracle, WS, Scrum

Experienced Engineer @ AKKA Benelux

[2013-11-2014-03]

**ETCS P.A. Tools** Application supporting the implementation of the ETCS system on the Belgian rail network Business modeler

JPA (EclipseLink), UML, NetBeans, Subversion, Domain-Driven Design

Senior Java EE Consultant @ Aubay

[2007-06—2013-10]

**Capelo** Application for collecting and validating civil servants' career data

Architect

JPA, EJB 3.0, Struts 1.x, JAX-WS, GWT, Maven, JBoss, Oracle, WebLogic, Subversion

**Argo** Application for centralizing and managing employee career data

Senio developer (v1.0), Architect (v2.0)

JPA, EJB 3.0, JBoss, WS, Oracle, Spring WebFlow, BPEL, Subversion

**Carat** Application for managing test configurations performed on electronic boxes embedded on satellites Analyse, design, data-model refactoring, coaching

Swing, JGoodies, Java Web Start, Ant, JPA, MySQL, ClearCase

#### Java EE Lead Architect @ Smals

[2005-01-2007-05]

Limosa Web application for the declaration of posting of foreign workers on Belgian territory

Global architecture, coaching, security

Hibernate, Spring, Struts 1.x, JMS, Axis, WebLogic, Oracle, Maven, CVS

STTS Web application for the management of social telephone tariff grants for BIPT

Global architecture, coaching

Hibernate, Spring, Struts 1.x, Axis, WebLogic, Oracle, Ant, CVS

Primaweb Web application for the management of social integration income grants and the Fuel Fund (CPAS)

Global architecture, coaching

Hibernate, Spring, Struts 1.x, Axis, WebLogic, Oracle, Ant, CVS

iBoss Web application for the management of labour audit files

Global architecture, coaching

Hibernate, Spring, Struts 1.x, JMS, Axis, WebLogic, Oracle, Maven, CVS

**Other** Design of project architectures, choice of technologies to be implemented, structure of the project tree, design of prototypes, development of critical parts, supervision and coaching of developers

(code reviews, peer-programming, mini-courses, guidelines documents)

Development of generic project models and reusable components

Design of a reference dossier management application serving as a basis for all the above-mentioned projects, emulation of a COBOL mainframe terminal in Swing, standardization of the basic types of social security (VAT numbers, national register numbers, etc.), standardization of the development of internal basic services

#### Java EE Architect Candidate @ Smals

[2004-01-2004-12]

**Genesis** Centralized dossier management application for social inspection services

Application architecture, used technologies, data-model design, user-interface design, coaching, work assignment

WebLogic, Oracle, JSP, Servlet, EJB, JMS, Hibernate, Struts, Ant, CVS, XML

#### Functional Analyst @ Smals

[2003-04-2003-12]

**Genesis** Centralized dossier management application for social inspection services
Business process and requirements analysis, customer interviews
UML, Catalyst

NatReg Web application for consulting the national register Requirements analysis, user-interface design UML, Catalyst

#### **Education**

Opleidingsinstituut van de Federale Overheid - Institut de Formation de l'Administration fédérale

**2017—2018** Dutch writing and speaking (level B1-B2)

Université Libre de Bruxelles (Formation continue)

**2011—2012** University certificate in IT project management (great distinction)

Centrum voor Volwassenenonderwijs Meise-Jette

2008—2009 Dutch conversation group

Université Libre de Bruxelles (Faculty of Applied Sciences / Polytechnic School)

**1997—2002** Master of Civil Engineering in Computer Science (distinction)

Collège Saint-Pierre de Jette

**1991—1997** High school

#### **Skills**

expert\*\*\* advanced\*\* novice\*

Languages French\*\*\*, Dutch\*\*, English\*\*, German\*

**Design** UML, C4 Model, Patterns, Object-Oriented, Test-Driven, Database Design, Aspect-Oriented, Domain-Driven, Event-Driven

**Technologies** Java\*\*\*, Hibernate\*\*\*, Spring\*\*\*, Struts\*\*\*, GWT\*\*, JUnit\*\*\*, Swing\*\*, Servlet\*\*\*, EJB\*\*\*, JPA\*\*\*, CDI\*\*\*, JMS\*\*, JSF\*\*, JAX-RS\*\*, JAX-WS\*\*, SQL\*\*\*, JavaScript\*\*, HTML\*\*\*, CSS\*\*, Python\*, XML\*\*\*, XSLT\*\*, XSD\*\*

**Tools** Eclipse\*\*\*, IntelliJ\*, NetBeans\*, Ant\*\*\*, Maven\*\*\*, Subversion\*\*, CVS\*\*, Git\*\*, JIRA\*, Mantis\*, Trac\*, Jenkins\*\*, Gerrit\*\*, GitLab\*\*

Servers JBoss / WildFly, Tomcat, Apache HTTPd, MySQL, Oracle DB, WebLogic, OpenEJB / TomEE

Interests Project Management (Agile, Scrum, Lean, Kanban, Prince2, PMI), Open Source Software, Rapid Application Development, Clean Design / Hexagonal Architecture, Hypermedia / RESTful APIs